<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[<span class="label" style="margin-right:10px;"><a href="/" style="text-decoration:none; text-transform:none; color:#fff">&larr;</a></span>Jekyll | Yo Briefcase!]]></title>
  <link href="http://yobriefca.se/blog/categories/jekyll/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://yobriefca.se/"/>
  <updated>2012-04-20T21:53:44+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://yobriefca.se/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[James Hughes]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The First Day of the Rest of My Life]]></title>
    <link href="http://yobriefca.se/blog/2011/05/16/the-first-day-of-the-rest-of-my-life/"/>
    <updated>2011-05-16T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://yobriefca.se/blog/2011/05/16/the-first-day-of-the-rest-of-my-life</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>  <p>Move complete, more or less.  Still a few broken images and stuff but like the unpacked boxes of a new house these will probably remain that way until about next year or so.  Decent enough weekend project all in.  For anyone who&#8217;s interested in what&#8217;s went on under the hood &#8211; read on.</p><h2>Abandoning Posterous</h2><p><a href="http://posterous.com">Posterous</a> is great as a simple blogging platform but in terms of giving me exactly what I wanted at any point in time <a href="http://posterous.com">Posterous</a> and most other platforms didn&#8217;t give me exactly what I wanted (I am quite a demanding character I guess).</p><p>I was doing some research on .<span class="caps">NET</span> Micro Web Frameworks and came across <a href="http://jessicafx.org">Jessica</a> which was created and maintained by <a href="http://tombell.org.uk">Tom Bell</a>.</p><h2>Jekyll</h2><p>Browsing Toms <a href="http://github.com/tombell">github repo</a> I discovered he prodced his site using <a href="https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll">Jekyll</a> a Ruby based static site generator and I knew I had to have it!  So I ripped off Toms nice design, uglified it with my own tweaks and what you see now is the finished site.  This site is also mirroed on <a href="http://kouphax.github.com">Github</a> but some of the functions (category pages) are missing due to some custom generators that the Github Jekyll instance doesn&#8217;t run.</p><p>There is more to be deployed but I&#8217;d rather polish what I have before pushing more stuff out.  I&#8217;ve tinkered with Project page generation, <a href="https://github.com/schacon/showoff">Showoff</a> for presentations and a few other things that will appear over time.</p><h2>Domain Name</h2><p>Seriously &#8211; how couldn&#8217;t I go for a shiny web 2.0 ultra elite domain name given the chance?  <a href="http://gandi.net">Gandi.net</a> was recommended to me and I must admit the set up was fairly painless and their admin panel stuff is very nice.</p><h2>Appharbor</h2><p>Currently my static site is hosted on <a href="http://appharbor.com">appharbor</a>.  Appharbor is awesome.  Typically I&#8217;ve used it to spin up quick demos and stuff and the simplicity of doing a <code>git push</code> to deploy your new version is like a dream (especially given the heavy handed approach of Azure).</p><h2>Thats It</h2><p>Not sure that anyone cares about this sort of stuff but I just want to take my new process for a spin anyway.  Any questions &#8211; let me know.</p></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
