<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[<span class="label" style="margin-right:10px;"><a href="/" style="text-decoration:none; text-transform:none; color:#fff">&larr;</a></span>Conference | Yo Briefcase!]]></title>
  <link href="http://yobriefca.se/blog/categories/conference/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://yobriefca.se/"/>
  <updated>2012-07-12T13:49:59+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://yobriefca.se/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[James Hughes]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Done Spoked at DevWeek]]></title>
    <link href="http://yobriefca.se/blog/2012/03/28/done-spoked-at-devweek/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-28T13:19:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://yobriefca.se/blog/2012/03/28/done-spoked-at-devweek</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>So I made it through my talk at DevWeek which might sound a little odd but it took a whole bottle of cough syrup to do it.  Not having been sick for most of the winter my body decided a day before DevWeek to go into shut down.  I spent Tuesday in bed with very little voice.  Thankfully the head colds hold on my vocal chords relented this morning and I think I managed to project as best I could.</p>

<p>So initial thoughts of how it went?  I honestly think I'm getting better at this presenting thing so that must be a good thing, unless I was TERRIBLE before.  The 2 main annoyances that have been raised thus far have been</p>

<h2>1. Too Short</h2>

<p>I did my usual "talk really fast and finish earlier than planned" thing I sometimes do. But there was plenty of discussion afterwards which I tought was interesting.  FWIW when I present this to myself it takes longer.  My internal monologue must be slower than the way I speak.  Apologies to anyone that felt it was "too short".</p>

<h2>2. Not enough Visual Studio</h2>

<p>I opted to play it safe end embed code into my slides rather than code live - I didn't go unnoticed and I had a few comments that "moar codez" would have been good.  Totally agree.</p>

<h2>Other Stuff</h2>

<p>I opted to change my slide deck between submitting them for print and presenting.  I did it out of desire to devlier a better, more structured, talk (my first set being quite short as I was going for a "free-form" type of presentation).  Probably not the most professional approach to do this but at least I can say my heart was in the right place :)  Here are offending articles BTW</p>

<div style="max-width:500px;margin:0 auto;">
    <script src="http://speakerdeck.com/embed/4f719e7aca692c002101c187.js"></script>
</div>


<p>Code that was presented is available, as always, in/on my <a href="https://github.com/kouphax/bddindotnet-code">Github Repo</a>.  Thanks to all who attended and any other feedback you have throw it my way so I can get better at this talking malarky.</p>

<p>Also thanks to the folks at DevWeek for the opportunity - hopefully you'll have me back at some point.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Talking at DDD North and Belfast]]></title>
    <link href="http://yobriefca.se/blog/2011/09/20/talking-at-ddd-north-and-belfast/"/>
    <updated>2011-09-20T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://yobriefca.se/blog/2011/09/20/talking-at-ddd-north-and-belfast</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The start of October is going to be a busy time for me - in a good way.  The first weekend I'll be doing two talks at <a href="http://developerdeveloperdeveloper.com/dddie11/Schedule.aspx">DeveloperDeveloperDeveloper in Belfast</a> and the following week I'll be skipping over to Sunderland (first time there) do do another talk for <a href="http://developerdeveloperdeveloper.com/north/Schedule.aspx">DeveloperDeveloperDeveloper North</a>.  I've been lucky enough to land the same presentation for both DDD Belfast and DD North which means I have slightly less to prepare.  Not that it will be a drop in quality in anyway - no siree.</p>

<p>For the interested folk the two talks are outlined below.  The titles and synopsis are fairly childish/over-sensationalised (delete as you see fit) but thats the way I roll.  My opinion enjoys being passed around and so my talks will feature a heavy dose of it - with all necessary disclaimers attached.</p>

<p>For both events I'll be covering,</p>

<blockquote><h1>refORM: Death to ORMs in .NET</h1>

<p>Data Access is a difficult area to master. There are plenty of frameworks such as Entity Framework, NHibernate, i/myBatis. These frameworks attempt to make data access simpler but while these products are widely used they can lead to leaky abstractions forcing us to work around constraints of the technology or introduce the nightmare of trying to figure out what is happening deep down in the frameworks internals.</p>

<p>In this session we will look at the various lightweight alternatives and the advantages they offer as well as provide rationale about why the more heavyweight approach isn't always the best approach.</p></blockquote>

<p>And for DDD Belfast only,</p>

<blockquote><h1>CoffeeScript the Awesome</h1>

<p>CoffeeScript - "a little language that compiles into JavaScript" has been making a lot of noise in the web community with its inclusion in Ruby on Rail v3 and its swift rise in popularity on Github.</p>

<p>This session will look at the benefits this language brings over the native JavaScript alternative, the syntactical double rainbow it creates, the problems you'll face and of course how you can actually use it in different technology stacks such as Ruby, node.js, .NET and Java.</p></blockquote>

<p>I've never really undertaken sessions of this size before (mostly internal or for a customer) so it's going to be a cracking experience.  Hopefully people get as much out of these sessions as I will.  I'll have whatever resources up after the events as well.</p>

<p>See you there (maybe).</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
