<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: PowerMockup | Yo Briefcase!]]></title>
  <link href="http://yobriefca.se/blog/categories/powermockup/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://yobriefca.se/"/>
  <updated>2012-03-12T19:38:56+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://yobriefca.se/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[James Hughes]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[PowerMockup – Wireframe Toolkit for PowerPoint]]></title>
    <link href="http://yobriefca.se/blog/2011/04/16/powermockup-wireframe-toolkit-for-powerpoint/"/>
    <updated>2011-04-16T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://yobriefca.se/blog/2011/04/16/powermockup-wireframe-toolkit-for-powerpoint</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>  <p>Link: <a href="http://www.powermockup.com/">http://www.powermockup.com/</a></p><blockquote>Disclosure Time:&nbsp; I approached the developer of this app offering to do a review in exchange for a review license.&nbsp; This isn&rsquo;t the sort of thing I usually blog about (except internally, a few times, in the company I work for) but I&rsquo;m all for supporting the people who deserve support and truth be told I would probably have written this blog post anyway (yep it&rsquo;ll be a positive one)</blockquote><p>Happy with that?&nbsp; Good lets crack on.</p><h2>The Past</h2><p>I&rsquo;ve written a fair number UI design documents over the last few years and for all of these I have used <a href="http://balsamiq.com">Balsamiq</a>.&nbsp; The problem with that is our companies standard/approved wire-framing solution is Visio (with the <a href="http://www.guuui.com/issues/02_07.php">GUUUI templates</a>).&nbsp; Why did I go against the grain? Well I am not a mad fan of Visio.&nbsp; It&rsquo;s not exactly lightweight, in fact it&rsquo;s extremely bloated (at least in the wire-framing sense), and that is easily the worst thing you can ask for when dealing with highly iterative, dynamic, interactive wire-framing.&nbsp; You need to work with the Visio rather than let Visio work for you and that is slightly too much fail for me most of the time.&nbsp; Admittedly there has been times I prefer the slicker, more professional, output of Visio (our customers come from the stiff collar world of finance and the like so it tends to sit better with them).&nbsp; But were I can I stick with Balsamiq.&nbsp; Until now....</p><h2>The Present</h2><p>The problem I&rsquo;ve always faced with Balsamiq is that when I produce a first draft of a document with, say, 20 odd wireframes in it and something fundamental is changed by the customer then I have a hard slog ahead to fix all those images.&nbsp; Thankfully a colleague of mine, one much better at this wire-framing/UX stuff than me, pointed me towards PowerMockup.&nbsp; Rather than make a new standalone application that has it&rsquo;s own random UI features and offers little to on integration into the app we use day today PowerMockup is simply an extension/add-on to Powerpoint.&nbsp; So what does this mean?&nbsp; Well it means,</p><ul><li>The devs spent more time into the templates and stuff that matter</li><li>Fully integrated into the Office application stack (think ability to tweak results when embedded into Word)</li><li>Already makes use of the built in &ldquo;smart&rdquo; styling and other features that make Powerpoint actually a fairly decent app for quick templating and stuff.&nbsp; In fact take it a step further and you could make use of Powerpoint&rsquo;s animation stuff to demonstrate UI interactions.</li></ul><p>So given 5 minutes what could I do?&nbsp; And I do mean 5 minutes (possibly slightly less).&nbsp; Well I mocked up the website you are reading right now.&nbsp;</p><p class="img-holder"><img src="http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3151/5720048084_8b4994da36_z.jpg"></p><p>Trippy eh?&nbsp; It&rsquo;s not my best work (far from it) but it did help me test drive PowerMockup and get a better feel of it.&nbsp; So I like it.&nbsp; I like it because of all the things I&rsquo;ve mentioned above (who wouldn&rsquo;t).&nbsp; I&rsquo;d use it, and will use it, as my wire-framing tool of choice (and not because I got a free license - my work would pay for it anyway cause they are total aces) from now on but it&rsquo;s not perfect.&nbsp; If I had to pick holes there are a few things that I&rsquo;d mention,</p><ul><li>My biggest peeve but it&rsquo;s not a show stopper is the location of the various shapes/widgets.&nbsp; Dropdowns are in &ldquo;Navigation&rdquo; and Text fields are in &ldquo;Text&rdquo; but 99% of the time I&rsquo;d want both of those when constructing a form.&nbsp; I&rsquo;d really like a &ldquo;Form&rdquo; collection with all of these things grouped.</li><li>If I drop a browser container on the page then drop a scrollbar on the page I need to resize said scrollbar to fit the browser container.&nbsp; Problem is, as the scrollbar is a grouped object, it will stretch the entire thing rather than extend the base rectangle.&nbsp; Again no show stopper but it is a bit of a pain.&nbsp; I guess offering the components as separate shapes might make it easier (just a suggestion).</li><li>There a plenty of icons but I&rsquo;d like to see a few more (&ldquo;comments&rdquo; icon, &ldquo;tags&rdquo; icon) - the equivalent famfamfam icon set would blow me away (and also a lot to ask).&nbsp; Possibly some more mobile shapes etc. would also be nice.</li></ul><h2>The Future</h2><p>So thats it for now I am very happy, not because I managed to blag a free license, but rather because the app/plugin/whatever fits into how I do things so seamlessly.&nbsp; Good work and I look forward to future updates - hopefully more people think the same.</p></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
